<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Lords-Justices of Ireland, a proclamation. Sydney, Tho: Coningsby. It having been observed that divers Papists, and others disaffected to the government, some of whom are lately come out of the enemies quarters, ...</title>
            <author>Ireland. Lords Justices and Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B24719</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886463</idno>
  <idno type="VID">186700</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2264216011</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I444</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R226049</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886463</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886463e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B24719)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186700)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C5:2[125]; C5:3[14])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Lords-Justices of Ireland, a proclamation. Sydney, Tho: Coningsby. It having been observed that divers Papists, and others disaffected to the government, some of whom are lately come out of the enemies quarters, ...</title>
                  <author>Ireland. Lords Justices and Council.</author>
                  <author>Coningsby, Thomas Coningsby, Earl, 1656?-1729.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Andrew Crook, assignee of Benjamin Tooke, printer to the King and Queens Most Excellent Majesties, on Ormonde Key,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from caption and opening words of text.</note>
                  <note>"Given at the castle of Dublin the twentieth day of November 1690. And in the second year of their Majesties reign.".</note>
                  <note>All Papists to leave Dublin.--Steele.</note>
                  <note>Steele notation: Arms 199. o- Rebellion 2) do Lord-.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Catholics --  Ireland --  Legal status, laws, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  War of 1689-1691 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="declaration">
            <pb facs="tcp:186700:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>English coat of arms, William III, circa 1690</figDesc>
                  <p>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</p>
                  <p>JE MEIN TIEN DRAY</p>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>BY THE LORDS-JUSTICES of IRELAND, A PROCLAMATION.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SYDNEY, THO: CONINGESBY.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>T having been observed that divers Papists, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers disaffected to the Government, some of whom are lately come out of the Enemies Quarters, do daily resort unto this City of <hi>Dublin,</hi> and into the Liberties of St. <hi>Sepulchers, Thomas-Court,</hi> and <hi>Donore,</hi> and do presume not only in the Day, but in the Night time, to meet in Numbers, to the Intent, as We have great reason to apprehend, then to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sult how to raise Disturbances, to the prejudice of Their Majesties Government, and to continue the Rebellion in this Kingdom, as also to destroy this City by Fire, which some of them (as we are credibly inform'd) have threat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, and design to do. For Remedy therefore of the Mischiefs which may hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen upon such Resort and Meetings, We do hereby strictly charge and require all Persons whatsoever of the Popish Religion, who have not been noted House-Keepers within the City or Liberties aforesaid, for the space of three months last past, that within forty eight Hours after the publishing of this our Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation, they do depart out of the said City and Liberties, and repair to their several Habitations, or other places in the Country, at least Ten Miles distant from this City, which is they shall neglect, or refuse to do, they shall be appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hended, and proceeded against, as Spies, and Persons designing the Disturbance of the Publique Peace; And in order to the more effectual Execution of the our Proclamation, We hereby require the Lord-Mayor and Sheriffs of the City of <hi>Dublin,</hi> and the Seneschals of the said Liberties, to cause diligent search and enquiry to be made, immediately after the time hereby limitted, for the depar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of such Persons as aforesaid, in all Houses and places throughout the said City and Liberties, and a true Account to be taken of the Names and Qualities of such as shall be found therein, not qualified as aforesaid, which is forthwith to be returned unto Us, under the hands of the said Lord-Mayor and Sheriffs, and Seneschals of the said Liberties, whereupon we will give Order to have them
<pb facs="tcp:186700:2"/>proceeded against with the utmost Rigour of Their Majesties Laws. And We do hereby further Declare, that if any such Papist, or other Disaffected Person, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the fourth day of <hi>December</hi> next, not being House Keepers as aforesaid, shall repair unto the said City or Liberties, and there abide by the space of twenty four Hours, after such Person or Persons shall come thither, without rendring him, her, or themselves, to the Lord-Mayor, or one of the Sheriffs or Aldermen of the said City, or one of the Seneschals of the said Liberties, to the end it may be known in what House or Parish, he, she, or they, take up his, her, or their Lodging, or if above the number of five Papists, or disaffected Persons as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, whether House-Keepers or others, shall presume to meet together in any House or place within the City or Liberties aforesaid, on any pretence what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soever, either by Day, or by Night, or shall be out of his, her, or their Lodging or Lodgings after nine of the clock at Night; In either of these cases, if any Person or Persons shall be so Hardy, as not to give due Obedience to our Directions aforesaid, they shall be prosecuted with the utmost severity, as Contemners of Their Majesties Royal Authority. And because Rewards as well as Punish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, are necessarily conducing to the Discovery of such as shall offend in the particulars aforesaid; We do hereby Publish and Declare, that as we will se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verely punish such Offenders as aforesaid, and the Receivers and Harbourers of them, contrary to this our Proclamation, so we will give a Reward of Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Shillings to each Person who shall give Information against any such Offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, in any of the aforesaid particulars, to be immediately paid out of their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties Treasury, upon Proof of such Offence or Offences, made before the Lord-Mayor of the said City.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given at the Castle of <hi>Dublin</hi>
                  <date>the Twentieth day of <hi>November</hi> 1690. And in the Second Year of their Majesties Reign.</date>
               </dateline> God Save the KING and QUEEN,
<signed>JO<seg rend="sup">N</seg>. DAVIS.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>DƲBLIN,</hi> Printed by <hi>Andrew Crook,</hi> Assignee of <hi>Benjamin Tooke,</hi> Printer to the King and Queens Most Excellent Majesties, on <hi>Ormonde-Key.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>